

Rohit Salecha is a technology enthusiast with over 10+ years of experience in hacking anything and everything that is running on binary and is on the ground including but not limited to Web Applications, Web-Service APIs and Mobile Applications (iOS and Android) and performed code reviews from quality assurance and security perspective.

He also loves to reverse engineer binaries and mobile applications and find and exploit vulnerabilities in them. He spends his free time learning new technologies, programming languages or maybe even tinkering with open source tools.

Associate Director (AD) - NotSoSecure, Mumbai (Nov 2016-Present)

As an AD, Rohit Salecha leads a team of more than 8 heads and he strongly believes that his growth depends on overall growth of his reportees. His job at NotSoSecure is divided into the following domains.

Security Automation

- He loves automating his tasks and has also blogged about few of them in the Technology section.
- He is a big fan of DevOps methodology and he loves to play around with tools like Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Vagrant and Ansible.
- At NotSoSecure he has built the entire DevSecOps course from ground-up involving plenty of automation.
- Hence, he is responsible for identifying tasks which can be automated at NotSoSecure.

Security Architecture Review/Threat Modelling

- Being a developer at heart Rohit has experience in understanding how a typical software development environment operates.
- He has performed architecture reviews of various such environments whether they are running in traditional IT or the modern DevOps stack.
- His architecture reviews involve understanding the current high-level architecture then drilling deep down into the technology stack and suggesting the security best practices.
- He has also worked with the STRIDE threat modelling approach by Microsoft in various projects.
- He has experience in performing architecture and configuration review from a security standpoint for on-premises as well as cloud infrastructure including technology like Kubernetes.

Strategy

- Being in the senior leadership Rohit Salecha is also tasked with steering the organization towards better growth.
- Aligning research with pentesting and training content development to maximize revenue.
- He is also tasked in leading the 'Protect and Detect'^{1*} segment to deliver strategic advises and consultancy to organizations for injecting security in their SDLC processes.
- Actively involved in recruitment process for hiring exceptional candidates who can grow along with the company

Pentesting

- Web, Mobile and API pentesting of applications from various industries
- Researching for new tools and techniques for pentesting by and feeding it back to the team.
- He is also very active on the CobaltCore^{2*} pentesting platform.

Training

- Lead trainer for three of the most selling classes of NotSoSecure viz.
 Application Security for Developers, DevSecOps and AppSecOps and delivered this class across the globe i.e. UK, EU and USA to various clients and training partners like QA and Checkpoint.
- Developed the entire DevSecOps course from ground up and presented at OWASP Global APPSEC DC and many more places.
- Trained and spoken at premier Security conferences like Blackhat, OWASP APPSEC, Nullcon and Agile+DevOps by Techwell.

- 1* https://www.claranetcybersecurity.com/protect-and-detect
- 2* https://app.cobalt.io/rsalecha

Work History

• IT Security Specialist – Emirates NBD, Dubai (April 2015- Nov 2016)

- Served as an internal Information Security consultant to the organization ensuring proper information security clearance amidst a constantly changing environment at the Bank.
- Risk Assessment of New Business Initiatives (Products, Channels, Solutions) across the bank from an Information Security and Architecture perspective ensuring involvement at every stage of the project/imitative lifecycle.
- Third Party (Vendor) Assessments through RFP sessions helping select the best vendor from a Security and Architecture perspective.

• IT Risk Advisory Consultant – EY, Mumbai (March 2014- April 2015)

- Performing Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration testing for EYs clients in the Telecom, Media & Entertainment and Technology domains.
- Performed IT Audits for ensuring compliance with various regulatory standards and policies including SOX and TRAI
- Developing and Reviewing Minimum Baseline Security Standards for various technologies

Security Analyst – NII Consulting, Mumbai (Aug 2012- March 2014)

- Performing VAPT on web/mobile applications and servers for various clients in the Banking industry and advising them on various security issues.
- Conducted CSJD (Certified Secure Java Development) trainings for NII's and IIS's premier clients and CSI (Computer Society of India) Mumbai Chapter.
- Delivered Security Awareness training to the senior management of a major Oil and Gas Corporation in India.
- Single-handedly managed a 3-month engagement for a leading insurance company to perform Secure Code review and developing security guidelines for developers in J2EE technology.

• Software Engineer – Mastek, Mumbai (July 2010- Aug 2012)

- Full stack developer in J2EE-Oracle technology with expertise in Spring, Struts, JPA, Hibernate, MySQL and Oracle
- Developed a suite of applications for MHADA Lottery 2012 following Secure Coding best practices as advised by the Security team over a period of 15 months.
- Developed J2ME Mobile applications for bus-tracking as part of a hackathon

Certifications

- **CKA** (Certified Kubernetes Admin) December 2020 (Valid)
- CISSP (Certified Information Systems Security Professional) July 2016 (Expired)
- OSCP (Offensive Security Certified Professional) October 2014 (Expired)

Technical Skillset (Hands-on Experience)

- Programming Languages: Java (Spring, Struts2), PHP, Python and Bash
- DevOps Tools: Jenkins, ELK Stack, HashiCorp Vault, GitHub Actions
- Platforms: Ubuntu, Windows, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS Cloud

Open Source Contributions

- Practical DevOps The Lab
- Contribution to Semgrep-Rules
- OWASP Cheatsheet Series

Links

- https://www.rohitsalecha.com/
- https://github.com/salecharohit
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohitsalecha/
- https://app.cobalt.io/rsalecha

Educational Background

B.E Electronics, Vidyalankar Institute of Technology, Wadala (2005-2009)

Other Than Work

- Being a triathlon enthusiast, his morning generally begins with either cycling, jogging or swimming
- A bibliophile he loves to read books fictional, non-fictional
- A movie bluff and a big fan of Christopher Nolan, Marvel and DC movies